<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code_and_softwares on KCNI WBMG</title><link>https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/</link><description>Recent content in Code_and_softwares on KCNI WBMG</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Virtual Brain (TVB) Platform</title><link>https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/tvb/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/tvb/</guid><description>The Virtual Brain (TVB) is a modelling and neuroinformatics platform for simulating meso-scale whole-brain neural activity. TVB is the brainchild of our colleagues Randy McIntosh Viktor Jirsa, and is one of the principal tools we use in our computational modelling research work.
As members of the &amp;lsquo;extended&amp;rsquo; TVB team, we provide technical support on the Forum, teach regularly at workshops, and develop new technical features and applications.
Newbies to TVB: check out the main website and the github organization; and particularly the jupyter notebook demos and tutorials.</description></item><item><title>eeg-notebooks</title><link>https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/eeg-notebooks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/eeg-notebooks/</guid><description>eeg-notebooks is a python-based software library that provides a simple end-to-end platform for conducting cognitive neuroscience experiments using consumer-grade EEG technology. It emerged out of the close relationship between our good friends at NeuroTechX and other other good friends at InterAxon (just down the road from CAMH). Using eeg-notebooks together with a standard laptop computer and ~$200 EEG headset such as the Interaxon MUSE, one can conduct high-quality event-related potential (ERP) experiments that traditionally require research-grade equipment costing tens of thousands of dollars.</description></item><item><title>ConWhAt</title><link>https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/conwhat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/conwhat/</guid><description>ConWhAt (for Connectome-based White matter Atlas Analyses) is a tool for studying the effects of white matter damage on brain networks.
Its primary functionality is connectome-based white matter atlas analysis, for which it uses a set of connectome-based white matter atlases developed by our research group for this purpose, as well as (optionally) similar atlases developed by other groups. ConWhAt can also be used for more conventional tract-based white matter atlas analysis, and more generally for querying how spatial locations in the white matter tissue relate to different grey matter regions and brain networks.</description></item><item><title>JDG Lab Notebook</title><link>https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/jdg_lab_notebook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://griffithslab.github.io/code_and_software/jdg_lab_notebook/</guid><description>Link here
The JDG LabNotebook is an online, digital lab notebook that has been used over the years as part technical blog, part project management tool, and part collaboration facilitator. Entries are generally a mix of text, code, and rich media.It has been used for both general notes and for research project documentation and collaboration, and so the site contains both open-access and password-protected + encrypted entries. Use the tags on the right hand side to list open access entries; all are welcome to peruse these and use any code goodies they find useful.</description></item></channel></rss>