<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on KCNI WBMG</title><link>griffithslab-website/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on KCNI WBMG</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="griffithslab-website/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BrainHack CAN Toronto</title><link>griffithslab-website/post/brainhack_can/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>griffithslab-website/post/brainhack_can/</guid><description>Last week we ran another successful brainhack workshop at Ryerson University&amp;rsquo;s Biomedical Zone, as a satellite event for the Canadian Neuroscience Association (CAN-ACN) conference, which was held in Toronto this year.
I&amp;rsquo;ve written previously about previous Toronto brainhacks and why I like them so much, so I won&amp;rsquo;t repeat all of that here. But here&amp;rsquo;s a very brief recap:
This figure from Craddock et al. 2016 conveys the key ideas nicely:</description></item><item><title>Towards standardization of computational models in neuroimaging</title><link>griffithslab-website/post/bids_compmodels_mtg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>griffithslab-website/post/bids_compmodels_mtg/</guid><description>Last week I spent a few days in Princeton at a small invited workshop aimed at developing a BIDS specification for computational models. Organizer Russ Poldrack succeeded in securing a very smart and capable list of attendees, including Petra Ritter, Tal Yarkoni, Randy McIntosh, Brad Love, Jonathan Cohen, Marmaduke Woodman, Tim Rogers, Rosalyn Moran, Chris Markiewicz, Padraig Gleeson, and many others.
The basic objectives were twofold. First, to identify the types of neuroimaging data commonly used in computational modelling of various flavours, and start work in developing a common vocabulary and file/folder nomenclature for them.</description></item><item><title>GriffLab opens for business</title><link>griffithslab-website/post/grifflab_opens/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>griffithslab-website/post/grifflab_opens/</guid><description>After several months&amp;rsquo; lead-in and build-up, I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to announce that the KCNI WBMG / GriffLab is now officially &amp;lsquo;open for business&amp;rsquo;. Recruitment is now getting underway for post-docs, graduate students, and undergrads (see here for more details). This ramp-up phase is being done in parallel with the KCNI computational genomics (triplab) and microcircuit modelling (haylab) groups, and there will be a lots of ideas, skills, and research exchange between our three teams in the coming months and years.</description></item></channel></rss>