<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on KCNI WBMG</title><link>/project/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on KCNI WBMG</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computational and theoretical models of brain dynamics</title><link>/project/secondary_areas/models_of_brain_dynamics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/secondary_areas/models_of_brain_dynamics/</guid><description>A main overarching theme of most of the work we do in the WBMG is meso/macroscopic computational models of neural dynamics. We use mathematical models describing neural population activity on the scale of millimetres to centimetres, together with network structure from macaque histology or diffusion MRI fibre tracking, to simulate (approximately) whole-brain activity measurements of the kind measured by fMRI and M/EEG. These techniques are gradually allowing us to obtain more mechanistic insights into observed patterns in neuroimaging data relating to the resting state, oscillations, and the impact of neurological and neurodegenerative disease.</description></item><item><title>Brain Networks</title><link>/project/primary_areas/brain_networks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/primary_areas/brain_networks/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Brain Rhythms</title><link>/project/primary_areas/brain_rhythms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/primary_areas/brain_rhythms/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Brain Stimulation</title><link>/project/primary_areas/brain_stimulation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/primary_areas/brain_stimulation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Modelling brain damage</title><link>/project/secondary_areas/brain_damage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/project/secondary_areas/brain_damage/</guid><description>The effects of white matter damage on cognitive and neural function is a subject of major interest for the group. Earlier work studied how different spatial profiles of damage following stroke resulted in differential types of linguistic impairments. A large part of our current work asks similar questions from a more systems level perspective: what is the impact of a given spatial profile of damage on the topological structure and dynamic behaviour in connectome-based neural mass models?</description></item></channel></rss>